export const Questions4 = [
    {
        question : 'What type of clothing became common among devout Muslims in Africa?',
        optionA: 'Traditional African clothing',
        optionB: 'Completely Islamic attire or Islamized African dresses',
        optionC: 'European-style clothing',
        optionD: 'Casual Western wear',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did European Christianity influence African marriage practices?',
        optionA: 'Encouraged polygamy',
        optionB: 'Promoted monogamy',
        optionC: 'Allowed multiple marriages without restriction',
        optionD: 'Abolished all marriage practices',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did Islamic chieftaincy titles influence traditional African titles?',
        optionA: 'They were replaced by entirely new titles',
        optionB: 'They were completely removed from use',
        optionC: 'They were integrated and Islamized',
        optionD: 'They remained unchanged',
        answer: 'C',
    },
    {
        question : 'What was one of the primary effects of European missionaries on African dressing culture?',
        optionA: 'Encouraged traditional African attire',
        optionB: 'Promoted European dressing styles',
        optionC: 'Allowed a mix of African and European clothing',
        optionD: 'Abolished all traditional clothing',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did Islamic education affect traditional African education?',
        optionA: 'It fully replaced it with Qur’anic schools',
        optionB: 'It complemented traditional education without replacing it',
        optionC: 'It had no impact on traditional education',
        optionD: ' It promoted Western education instead',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'Which type of education system replaced traditional African education due to Christian missionary activities?',
        optionA: 'Islamic education        ',
        optionB: 'Western education',
        optionC: ' Indigenous education',
        optionD: 'Oral education',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did Christianity impact traditional African burial rites?',
        optionA: 'Introduced evening wake-keeping',
        optionB: 'Encouraged midnight burials',
        optionC: 'Eliminated all burial rites',
        optionD: 'Promoted traditional rites without changes',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'What was one major reason for the formation of African Independent Churches?        ',
        optionA: 'To promote European cultural impositions',
        optionB: 'To retain African traditional practices like polygamy',
        optionC: 'To abolish all forms of Christianity',
        optionD: 'To align with Islamic practices',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'Which aspect of African worship did mission churches attempt to change, leading to the rise of African Indigenous Churches?',
        optionA: 'Use of drums',
        optionB: 'Emotional and enthusiastic worship',
        optionC: 'Use of traditional chants',
        optionD: 'Performance of traditional dances',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'What impact did Christianity have on African traditional medicine?',
        optionA: 'Promoted traditional healing',
        optionB: 'Completely replaced it with Western medicine',
        optionC: 'Encouraged a blend of traditional and Western medicine',
        optionD: 'Ignored traditional practices',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did Christianity influence the status of women in African societies?',
        optionA: 'Elevated the status of women to equal levels',
        optionB: 'Reinforced traditional subjugation',
        optionC: 'Removed women from societal roles',
        optionD: 'Created new societal roles for women',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'Which African traditional practice was incorporated into Christian worship by African Indigenous Churches?',
        optionA: 'Harvest festivals',
        optionB: 'Traditional healing rituals',
        optionC: 'Animal sacrifices',
        optionD: 'Polygamy',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'What was one major effect of Islam on African education systems?',
        optionA: 'Increased focus on Western education',
        optionB: "Replacement of traditional education with Qur’anic schooling",
        optionC: 'Complete elimination of all educational practices',
        optionD: 'Reinforcement of oral educational traditions',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'How did Islam influence African marriage practices compared to Christianity?',
        optionA: ' It allowed polygamy up to four wives',
        optionB: 'It completely banned polygamy',
        optionC: 'It promoted monogamy',
        optionD: 'It allowed unlimited polygamy',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'In what way did Islam impact the place of women in traditional African society?',
        optionA: 'Reinforced traditional marginalization',
        optionB: "Completely eliminated women's rights",
        optionC: "Recognized women's rights and allowed property inheritance",
        optionD: 'Banned women from public life',
        answer: 'C',
    },
    {
        question : 'Which language gained prominence among some African communities due to Islam?',
        optionA: 'French',
        optionB: 'Arabic',
        optionC: 'Swahili',
        optionD: 'Portuguese',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'What has replaced traditional African greetings among devout Muslims?',
        optionA: 'French salutations',
        optionB: 'Arabic phrases',
        optionC: 'Western-style greetings',
        optionD: 'Local dialect expressions',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'Which title is an example of the Islamization of traditional African chieftaincy titles?',
        optionA: ' Ìyá Adinni',
        optionB: 'Chief of the Tribe',
        optionC: 'King of the Region',
        optionD: 'High Priest',
        answer: 'A',
    },
    {
        question : 'What impact did Islam have on traditional African medicine?',
        optionA: 'It completely rejected traditional practices',
        optionB: 'It introduced Islamic remedies like Tirah and hanntu',
        optionC: 'It encouraged the use of only herbal remedies',
        optionD: 'It had no impact on medical practices',
        answer: 'B',
    },
    {
        question : 'What was a common criticism of the early European Christian missionaries in Africa?',
        optionA: 'They promoted local traditions',
        optionB: 'They respected indigenous cultures',
        optionC: 'They imposed European culture and civilization',
        optionD: 'They ignored local languages',
        answer: 'C',
    }
]